I think there's a strong possibility
that we're at a turning point in history
a complete revolution in human affairs
with a discovery of totally new energy
sources many people are skeptical of
this but I think we may be going through
the four stages involved any
revolutionary development one it's
nonsense don't waste my time two oh it's
interesting but not important three I
always said it was a good idea and four
I thought of it
[Applause]
[Music]
first can you imagine what it would be
like if you could split water and run it
into your engines you could put water in
your fuel tank to fly airplanes
power power
stations ordinarily we look at water to
drink and the wor our clothes today you
have to look at water as a fantastic new
fuel
[Music]
source a world powered by water might
seem like a dream a Pure Fantasy but 100
years ago that is exactly what the men
of steam would have thought about a
world powered by oil
[Music]
well it was during the Oil Embargo of
the United States it alarmed me that a
little country over in the in the Far
East could actually the United
States and realizing that the entire
industrial base of the United States and
and the world is based on the supply and
utilization of energy it became
imperative that we must try to bring in
an alternate fuel source and do it very
quickly of course I thought originally
with the right type of funding uh we
could possibly get it in within six
months but uh reality shows that the the
12 to 15 years was more uh correct in
this projection
back in the 70s stanmar set out
single-handedly to solve America's
energy problems he decided to do it
using water the world's most abundant
Storehouse of hydrogen which is a far
more powerful fuel than oil for 15 years
Ma has been fighting to get his
inventions taken
seriously most inventors uh have to be a
loner you have to be somewhat thicked
skinn and don't rely on other people to
support you because they will not more
times than not uh invention is really
stolen from the inventors even in my
prior development of high technology
I've had uh patents taken from me I
learned from the School of Hard Knocks
to be very cautious Ma has always stood
out against the crowd he has no formal
qualifications as a scientist because he
didn't wait to graduate from high school
leaving early to go straight into
research at the high powered battel
Institute in his native Ohio now he
works full-time as a private inventor
his goto device with potentially
revolutionary
implications there is nothing startling
about a machine that can extract the
hydrogen from water what is highly
unusual is that it should do so with
ordinary tap water conventional method
is called
electrolysis May has turned that process
on its head unlike electrolysis his
device doesn't use up large amounts of
electric current nor does it produce an
enormous amount of waste
heat for 20 years he has been refining a
method to fracture water which produces
vast amounts of hydrogen on
demand this is not his latest apparatus
he was unwilling to let us point a
camera at that this is the simple device
he used to convince a reluctant patent
office that his revolutionary concept
actually
[Music]
works alloy rods acting as electrodes
are housed in a perspect container
that's filled with
water normal Main's voltage is fed in
through a Transformer but critically
there is virtually no current consumed
less than half an amp the result is
dramatic hydrogen pours off with the
flick of a
switch me claims the key is his
electronics which pulses electricity
rapidly across the rods up to 20,000
cycles per second in a way that's not
readily apparent this process transforms
the equation whereas in conventional
electrolysis three times as much energy
is consumed as is produced in the form
of hydrogen fuel in Mars apparatus the
reverse is true it appears to produce
several 100% more energy than it
consumes Stan has something that's
characteristic of the people that sound
like they've done something to tap Z
Point
Energy uh has high frequency high
voltage and there's a combination of the
two at which something
occurs uh with ch net ski in Russia it
was what he called a self- sustaining
discharge the tube would run by itself
when Stan gets this effect the amount of
hydrogen and oxygen that are are emitted
off these two electrodes is a step
function it almost boils the water if I
did this with standard electrochemicals
I need current and the water should
rise a degree every couple of seconds
withstands it it'll run for a half hour
and you and the water temperature hasn't
changed something's
different ma demonstrates this
repeatedly without any difficulty and
yet on the face of it it represents an
extraordinary Revolution his
measurements over the years suggest
1700% greater efficiency than
conventional
electrolysis and if he's to be believed
he's getting much better results from
his latest still secret
invention well I think just got involved
with stanm when I went over there with a
couple of colleagues to to look at his
water splitting device so we arrived at
Stanley may he had a demonstration cell
we filled it with tap water in fact I
did that myself and he switched it on
and almost instantly there were three
Jaws dropped because of the the rate at
which the gas poured off it was quite
spectacular whatever energy source Stan
Meyer had tapped it was not explicable
by the electric power that was going
into it so something was powering it
outside of conventional
wisdom there is no question that the gas
coming off in such abundance is hydrogen
Mar ignites it to produce a high
temperature flame able to cut through
metal Stanley May has faced a lot of
difficulties um he's three times tried
to launch the device and produced press
conferences at the technical press round
but he's been almost universally slated
in the early days very much so they just
ridiculed the whole idea he's getting a
little more notice now because some
scientists are getting interested but by
and large science is very intolerant
particularly modern
science as with Tesla Griggs and others
Myers claims are so far outside the
received scientific wisdom that they've
been ignored by the majority of the
scientific establishment but then may
has ignored them too he has poured his
energies over the last 10 years into
establishing recognition for his claims
by getting international
patents in the processing there was a
great deal of difficulty in trying to
process the legal paperwork in such a
way as to allow the patent office to
fully understand what was actually
occurring and one instant uh we brought
the water fuel cell uh to Washington DC
and of course I had tweaked it in such a
way to produce an enormous amount of
hydrogen oxygen gas and the patent
examiner said no it will not work uh
based on electrolysis process and uh
when we turned it on and produced
enormous amount of hydrogen gas uh The
Examiner finally realized that we were
doing exactly that and uh went out in
the hallway and started screaming and
hollering to everybody on the floor put
out all your cigarettes hydr hydrogen in
the building so we started laughing and
said well we certainly convinced
everybody in the patent office that we
can do what we say we can
do even so the US patent office dragged
their feet for 3 years before granting
patents on the hydrogen producing device
since then against Massive Resistance
he's managed to get patents established
throughout Europe and
Japan but the hydrogen machine was only
the first step towards Mar's Ultimate
Dream if he gets it right this
application of his technology would
change the 21st century in the same way
that the Wright brothers and Carl Ben
transformed the 20th he is currently
modifying a beach buggy to run on
nothing but
water it doesn't have a petrol tank or
even a hydrogen container it has just a
tank of water
he's invented a device called a water
splitter to replace the spark
plug as the water is injected into the
engine my claims it's fractured into
hydrogen and oxygen and then burned as
fuel m is working on a kit to modify any
engine he hopes to demonstrated on this
car within 12
months and of course the blessing to the
use of the water as a fuel source uh
that on combustion the byproduct is
water Miss so we're even solving the
environmental pollution problem at the
same time that we're using water to
maintain the industrial basis of the
world Mah is protective about his
inventions to the point of
self-confessed paranoia most observers
describe him as a crank and his car as
an aberration but then Madness and
genius often go hand inand Mar shares
with many inventors a problem that goes
well beyond paranoia as an engineer with
no scientific background he faces a
giant hurdle when he tries to
communicate with
Scientists one problem is that the
language that people use when they're
trying to describe their inventions is
not the language that I as a scientist
am used to and so I have to translate it
if you like into a way that I can begin
to understand what they're trying to say
it might as well be written in swal for
all of the sense that it initially makes
and so I'm not particularly inspired to
put a lot more effort in than the hope
the pearl of wisdom will reveal itself
to me a certain point you hit a law of
diminishing
returns it isn't just a question of the
difficulties of communication there is a
profound barrier between scientists and
inventors and a strong reluctance on the
part of most scientists to risk their
reputations grappling with issues that
don't have a clear scientific
pedigree reluctance to look foolish
inhibits a lot of people from looking at
things things this is looked at as a
pariah you get you touch it and it it
creates an image of you that you don't
want your colleagues to see one extreme
you might have things that are
guaranteed to work but are not very
interesting if they do and at The Other
Extreme things that are a real long shot
but would be revolutionary and so you
have to try and weigh the balance and
decide which side is more likely to be
profitable for you then having made some
choices you then have to ask yourself
how do I actually go about doing this do
I have to apply for funds to do it and
if I do who will I be competing with and
what is the better chance that this will
be supported or that because at least in
the big science area that I work you
can't just sort of come up with an idea
on a Friday and expect to start the
experiment on a Saturday it takes many
months many years even of
preparation but there the scientific
establishment may have ignored the likes
of Meer a powerful military-industrial
complex certainly hasn't
over the past 10 years Meer says he's
been quietly approached by many
influential organizations who would
never admit publicly to their
involvement with
him it is involved in deep space
exploration and it's also uh being
developed quite highly in the
military basically what occurred with
water fuel cell was in the fact that
once they
understood uh was actually occurring
then under the US National Security uh
mandate uh I have no
of power whether or not the military or
NASA or the federal government will
utilize the technology they can utilize
it in any way they so
desire NASA is using every method it can
to regain some of its now fading glory
in the face of strong Congressional
resistance the days of Limitless budgets
for space exploration have long since
gone as the champion of a new
environmentally friendly energy source
NASA would gain immense support your
identification
please you have your ID identification
as a former top scientist of the NASA
space Band project Professor Paul ziss
has an inside track on the workings of
the
agency NASA has large centers the center
that's in charge of propulsion is NASA
Lewis in Cleveland Ohio can you
imagine instead of having a um a million
pound rocket has 900,000 lbs of fuel on
board and
oxidizer can you imagine what it would
be like if you could put a device on
there that would split water and run it
into your engines no explosive
compounds public confirmation of a
contract from NASA would provide a
resounding boost for Ms
technology Paul says it's only in a
closed meeting they confirm such an
agreement they're looking for new energy
sources I understand from the people
that I've talked with that they have
worked with Stan and Tred to understand
understand what he's done and given him
a contract I also understand with the
bureaucracy in Washington and the con
Congressional oversight as to why they
would never admit it anyone that does
that will be suspect will be challenged
will be considered a
[Music]
threat but if only a fraction of what
Meer claims for his technology can be
achieved it would represent a
Vindication for NASA's involvement would
also be a powerful threat to many
entrenched vested interests if Stan
Meyer's device works like he
advertises you would make energy
available universally almost
free that is a major major major
impact when new technology comes in
existence there's a great resistance to
it uh because it can affect a lot of
economic factors uh in this particular
case in the United States um we pay out
roughly about $200 billion dollar a year
for foreign oil uh it's quite obvious
that uh the Arabs would pay $200 billion
to try to keep this type of Technology
uh out of the
economy and many many times over the
last decade I have been offered enormous
amounts of money to Simply sell out or
to sit on it the Arabs offer me well
over a billion dollars cold Cas simply
just sit on and do absolutely nothing
with it
my life has been uh threatened many
times of course I happen to believe in
the power of angels and if I don't
believe in the power of angels I don't
believe I'll be around here too
long if the thing like Stan mayor has
works every piston engine every gas
turbine in the world today if it had his
converter could run on it uh with a
little invention we could get Standalone
devices to run over all over the
world um I think it would be in what I
would can be concerned about is the
people that sell energy would be
essentially bankrupted it's what
happened to the conestogo wagons when
trains came or to the Pony Express when
the telegraph came in you're going to
wipe out an entrenched power base and
they may not go easily